admitad.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy: Admitad affiliate network

This Privacy Policy offers you information on how Admitad GmbH, Lise-Meitner-Str. 8, 74074 Heilbronn, Germany (hereinafter “Admitad” or “we/us/our”) deal with your personal and non-personal data whether you visit our website [www.admitad.com](https://www.admitad.com/), whether we collect data from you as an advertiser or a publisher or whether you are a user of our advertisers' or publishers’ websites and platforms.

## 1\. Definitions   

### 1.1 Personal data

“Personal data” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person; an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

### 1.2 Non-personal data  

“Non-personal data” means any information that cannot be related to your identity and therefore cannot be classified as personal data, like e.g. information on browser types, operating systems, domain names, access dates and times, referring website addresses, online transactions and browsing and search activity.

### 1.3 Processing

“Processing” means any operation or set of operations which is performed on data such as collection, recording, organizing, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction.

## 2\. Collecting and processing of personal data

The scope of how we collect and process personal and non-personal data on you or other information depends on the way you get in touch with us or our technologies and services:

  * as a visitor of www.admitad.com;
  * as a publisher or an advertiser of the Admitad affiliate network;
  * as a user of our publishers’ and advertisers’ websites.

With this Privacy Policy, we want to keep you informed which information we receive and use on every stage.

We use personal data only for administering and providing our technologies and services. We store personal and any other kind of data strictly in compliance with applicable data protection and privacy legislation and our contractual duties, and will prevent unauthorized access to data to the best of our abilities.

We do not transmit data to other third parties unless you have given your consent thereto or the transmission is made to state institutions on the basis of mandatory national legislation or other categories of recipients stated in section 3.

### 2.1 If you are a visitor of [www.admitad.com](https://www.admitad.com/)

If you visit the Admitad website, no personal data is collected and recorded unless you provided it voluntarily, e.g. as part of a survey. However, we log the following non-personal data to facilitate the use of our website and to ensure its security and stability our web servers:

  * the IP address of the requesting device;
  * the date and time of your visit;
  * the data specifications of your browser and operating system;  
  * the website you were referred from to our website (so-called Referrer URL).  

This information is stored in a log file until it is automatically deleted.  

#### 2.1.1. Cookies

We use [cookies](https://help.admitad.com/en/glossary/7-cookie/) to improve and optimize the usability of our website. Cookies do not cause damage to your device, do not contain viruses, trojans or other malicious software. The cookie stores information, which is linked to the respective device used. This does not mean, however, that we store personal information about you or are aware of your identity.

Visiting and surfing on our website is possible without cookies. Most browsers accept cookies automatically. You may alter the security settings of your web browser in order to stop your device receiving and storing cookies, to allow receiving and storing cookies from selected websites only, or to be notified before receiving cookies. Please note, however, that these settings may have negative effects on the usability and user guidance of websites and other online services. You may delete cookies stored in your browser at any time. Information stored in such cookies will be removed from your device.

Cookies used on our website are listed below.

**Domain** | **Cookie name** | **Cookie lifetime** | **Cookie description and purpose**  
---|---|---|---  
.admitad.com | csrftoken | 1 year | 

Stores the token for preventing CSRF attacks. The cookie is set when a user visits the website.

_Example:_ GeNDzySIugEz764zQMw pOA6OuWejCYRc  
  
.admitad.com | cookies_agreement | 30 days | 

Analytic cookie. Set if a non-Russian user clicks “Continue” on the Cookie Policy Notification Bar and thus agrees to the Admitad Cookie Policy.

_Example:_ yes  
  
.admitad.com | sb-closed | 15 days | 

Analytic cookie. Used only for users who came to the Admitad website from Android or MacOS devices. Set when a user closes a notification bar that suggests installing an Admitad application.

_Example:_ true  
  
.admitad.com | sb-installed | 90 days | 

Analytic cookie. Used only for users who came to the Admitad website from Android or MacOS devices. Set when a user clicks on the “Open” button on the Admitad app notification bar.

_Example:_ true  
  
.admitad.com | _gat ** ** | 10 minutes | Analytic cookie by Google Analytics. Limits the frequency of requests  
.admitad.com | _ga | 2 years | Analytic cookie by Google Analytics. Allows to identify users  
.admitad.com | _gid | 24 hours | Analytic cookie by Google Analytics. Allows to identify users  
.admitad-connect.com | _cfduid | 5 years | 

CloudFlare cookie. Allows identifying trusted web traffic.  
  
www.admitad.com | pw_* |   | Push World cookie.  
.admitad.com | etg | 

No expiration date

| Cookie set by a JavaScript library (Evercookie). Based on an HTTP header.  
.admitad.com | png | No expiration date | Cookie set by a JavaScript library (Evercookie). Based on cached PNG images.  
.admitad.com | cachec | No expiration date | Cookie set by a JavaScript library (Evercookie). Based on a browser history.  
.admitad.com | _ym_isad | 24 hours | Cookie by Yandex.Metrica. Allows defining an ad blocker presence.  
.admitad.com | _ym_uid | 2 years | Cookie by Yandex.Metrica. Allows defining user ID.  
.admitad.com | ya-disable | 100 years | Opt-out for Yandex.Metrica  
.admitad.com | fb-disable | 100 years | Opt-out for Facebook  
.admitad.com | ga-disable-UA-27907146-1 | 100 years | Opt-out for Google Analytics  
  
#### 2.1.2 Social plugins and analyzing tools

Admitad uses Facebook pixel, Yandex.Metrica and Google Analytics. Below you can learn more about how they use your information and, if you avoid connecting to plugins, find out how to opt-out.

This processing of (personal) data is necessary for our legitimate interests (i.e. marketing by increasing the range of our website/services), Art. 6 sec. 1 lit. f GDPR.  

##### 2.1.2.1 Facebook

Facebook is a social network of Facebook Ireland Limited, Hanover Reach, 5-7 Hanover Quay, Dublin 2, Ireland (hereinafter „Facebook“). On our website, we have included Facebook pixel. For a summary of Facebook pixel please refer to <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/facebook-pixel>.

When you enter a page on our website that contains a Facebook pixel your browser or app will establish a direct connection to Facebook’s servers where the pixel is loaded from. The information that your browser has visited the corresponding page of our online services will be transmitted to Facebook, even if you do not have a Facebook account or are not logged into your account. This information (including your IP address) will be sent by your browser directly to a server of Facebook in the USA and stored there.

If you are logged into your Facebook account at the same time, it is also possible to assign the page impression to your Facebook profile. If you click on embedded Facebook buttons and log into your Facebook account (or are already logged in), this information will be sent directly to a Facebook server and stored there. The corresponding information is published on your Facebook profile and in your chronicle/timeline in short form. Facebook can thus collect and store additional usage data. If you want to prevent the transmission and storage of your data and your behavior on our online services through Facebook, you must use the opt-out solution:

You can also change your Ad Settings here: <https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen> or log out of your Facebook account before you visit our sites and delete any cookies placed by Facebook.  

For more information on your rights and on how Facebook is recording and processing data please see Facebook’s Data Privacy Policy which is available at <http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/> and <https://www.facebook.com/help/443483272359009#!/help/340599879348142/>.  

##### 2.1.2.2 Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics which is a web analyzing tool of Google Inc., Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (hereinafter “Google“) for the purposes of the adequate design and continuous optimization of our website. Google Analytics works with cookies and creates pseudonymized usage profiles, which enable an analysis of your use of our website. Information stored in such cookies (such as browser type/version, an operating system used, referrer URL, Hostname of the accessing computer, time of server request) is usually transmitted to and stored on Google’s servers.

Due to the activation of the IP anonymization (IP masking), Google will truncate and therefore anonymize the IP address of your device within the European Union or the European Economic Area.

We contracted Google to analyze your use of this website in order to produce reports on the activities on our website and provide more services connected to the use of our website and the internet in general. We also use Google Analytics for marketing purposes: it allows us to advertise on third party websites (including Google) to previous visitors to our website.

The IP address provided by your browser will not be combined with other Google data. The information may be transferred to third parties if this is required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google. You can prevent cookies from being stored on your device by adjusting your browser software accordingly. Please note, however, that changing your settings may have negative effects on the usability of our website. You may prevent Google from recording and processing data on your use of our website (including your device’s IP address) and storing such information in a cookie by using an opt-out solution:

You also can download and install a browser deactivation add-on from <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

For more information, see Google privacy policy: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.  

##### 2.1.2.3 Yandex.Metrica **  **

We use Yandex.Metrica Service, accessible at <http://api.yandex.com/metrika/>, which enables the User’s different services and applications to interact with the Yandex.Metrica Service of Yandex. Yandex.Metrica works with cookies and creates pseudonymized usage profiles, which enable an analysis of your use of our website. Information stored in such cookies (such as browser type/version, an operating system used, referrer URL, Hostname of the accessing computer, time of server request) is usually transmitted to and stored on Yandex’s servers.

Due to the activation of the IP anonymization (IP masking), Yandex will truncate and therefore anonymize the IP address of your device within the European Union or the European Economic Area.

We contracted Yandex to analyze your use of this website in order to produce reports on the activities on our website and provide more services connected to the use of our website and the internet in general. We also use Yandex.Metrica for marketing purposes: it allows us to advertise on third party websites (including Yandex) to previous visitors to our website.

The IP address provided by your browser will not be combined with other Yandex data. The information may be transferred to third parties if this is required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Yandex. You can prevent cookies from being stored on your device by adjusting your browser software accordingly. Please note, however, that changing your settings may have negative effects on the usability of our website. You may prevent Yandex from recording and processing data on your use of our website (including your device’s IP address) and storing such information in a cookie by using an opt-out solution:

You also can download and install a browser deactivation add-on from <https://yandex.com/support/metrica/general/opt-out.xml>  

For more information, see Yandex privacy policy: <https://yandex.ru/legal/confidential/?lang=en>  

### 2.2 If you are a publisher or an advertiser

#### 2.2.1 Registration to and participation in our network

To obtain access to our technologies and services, you need to register in our network. After that in addition to the data described in section 2.1, we collect and process

  * personal data you specified in your registration form: your name, country, email address, etc.  
and
  * data you provide during your participation inAdmitad, e.g. your phone number, postal address or tax number

This processing of personal data is necessary for the performance of a contract, Art. 6 sec. 1 lit. b GDPR.

We do not collect or use any further personal data other than voluntarily provided by you.  

#### 2.2.2 Cookies

In addition to cookies specified in the section 2.1.1, we use the following cookies on the publisher and advertiser account pages:

**Domain** | **Cookie name** | **Cookie lifetime** | **Cookie description and purpose**  
---|---|---|---  
.admitad.com | sessionid | 14 days | 

Stores the ID of a user’s session. The cookie is set when a user signs in and is used to restore the session without entering the personal data.

_Example:_ 8vwhbmlf7flslzeawdhfgjbksfttc2v9  
  
.admitad.com | 

section

| 1 year | 

Stores the role of a user in the system (advertiser or publisher) selected during the first visit. The cookie is used to identify the user’s role correctly.

_Example:_ webmaster  
  
.admitad.com | user_default_language | 1 year | 

Records the code of the language selected by a user during the first visit.  
The cookie is used to identify the user’s language correctly.

_Example:_ en  
  
.admitad.com | promo_* | 7 days | 

Stores the ID of an affiliate program that is advertised in the system. The cookie is set when a user views information about the affiliate program and is used to keep the statistics on impressions for this program.

_Example:_ 15955  
  
.admitad.com | admitadec | > 10 years | Identifies Admitad users based on their accounts.  
.admitad.com | inviter | 1 year | 

Stores a [referrer](https://help.admitad.com/en/glossary/46-referrer/)’s code (if the referrer is an affiliate program, its code is also added).

The cookie is set when a potential publisher follows a referrer’s [referral link](https://help.admitad.com/en/glossary/48-referral-link/). If a [referral](https://help.admitad.com/en/glossary/45-referral/) gets a reward, the referrer will receive a commission from the system, while the referral’s reward will remain the same.

_Example:_ b260ff15f2  
  
www.admitad.com | ref_subid | 1 year | 

Stores [subid](https://help.admitad.com/en/topic/82-what-is-subid/).  
The cookie is set when a potential publisher follows a referrer’s referral link that contains subid. It is used to keep the referrer’s statistics.

_Example:_ tsdf89sdfjlj98  
  
www.admitad.com | adref | 1 year | 

Stores the code of the bonus for registration.  
The cookie is set when a potential publisher follows a special bonus link.  
If a publisher participates in a bonus program and earns the bonus, they can withdraw the money.

_Example:_ yu1dgmhfbz4bmxvq5bg9h35mg696 7nn6  
  
.admitad.com | admitadglobal | 2 years | 

The cookie is used if a publisher follows the affiliate link of an “[Admitad Global](https://www.admitad.com/en/webmaster/offers/1182/#information)” affiliate program. Tracks the publisher’s impressions of the “Admitad Global” affiliate program in the statistics. Its value shows if the bonus can be paid.

_Example:_ 1  
  
.admitad.com | adchc | 1 day | 

Used by some advertisers to run a test. Stores the value that shows whether the cookie is set or not when a user follows the special URL.

_Example:_ 1  
  
#### 2.2.3 Analysing tools

We use Google Analytics and Yandex.Metrica on account pages. More information is available here.

#### 2.2.4 Newsletters

With the following information, we will inform you about the contents of our newsletter as well as the registration, dispatch, statistical evaluation procedure and your right of objection. By subscribing to our newsletter, you agree to the receipt of the newsletter and the procedures described.

We send out newsletters, e-mails and other electronic notifications with promotional information (hereinafter "Newsletter") subject to the consent of the recipient or a legal permission.

The registration for our newsletter is handled through a so-called double opt-in procedure, which means you will receive an e-mail after your registration, in which you will be asked to confirm your registration once again. The registrations for the newsletter are recorded in order to prove the accurate registration process according to legal requirements. This includes storing the time of 

logon

and confirmation. Furthermore, changes to the data stored by GetResponse and Mindbox are being recorded.

The newsletters can be sent by Admitad itself or by means of third-party services named "GetResponse" and "Mindbox". GetResponse is a newsletter platform of the Polish company GetResponse Sp. z o.o. (a Polish limited liability company) // Arkonska 6, A3 80-387 Gdansk, Poland. Mindbox is a newsletter platform of the Dutch company Mindbox.Cloud B.V. (a Dutch private limited company) // Strawinskylaan 613, 1077XX Amsterdam, Netherlands.

The e-mail addresses of our newsletter recipients, as well as further data described in the context of this information, are being stored on the servers of Admitad GmbH, GetResponse and Mindbox. GetResponse and Mindbox use this information to send out and evaluate the newsletters on our behalf. In addition, GetResponse and Mindbox can use this data to optimize or improve their own services, e.g. for the technical optimization of the dispatch and the presentation of the newsletter or for economic purposes in order to determine from which countries the recipients come from. However, neither GetResponse nor Mindbox use the data of our newsletter recipients to contact them independently or transfer data to third parties except in cases prescribed by GetResponse privacy policy (<https://www.getresponse.com/legal/privacy.html>) and Mindbox personal data policy (<https://mindbox.cloud/documents/policy/>).

In order to register for the newsletter, we only need your e-mail address. Further voluntarily provided information about you is only used to personalize the newsletter. You can change your data at any time.

There are cases when we direct the newsletter recipients to the GetResponse or Mindbox websites. For instance, our newsletters contain a link with which the newsletter recipients can access the newsletters online (for example, in the case of display problems in the e-mail program).

You may terminate the receipt of our newsletter at any time, which means you revoke your consent. Therewith your consent to the dispatch of the newsletter via GetResponse and Mindbox as well as the statistical analyses expires at the same time. A separate cancellation of the dispatch via GetResponse or Mindbox or the statistical evaluation is unfortunately not possible. You may withdraw your consent to receive our newsletter at any time by changing the notification settings in your account. Besides, you will find a link to unsubscribe from our newsletter at the bottom of each newsletter.

### 2.3 If you are a user of our publishers’ and advertisers’ websites and platforms

#### 2.3.1 Cookies

We store cookies on devices of users who are visiting websites/platforms and using online services of our publishers and advertisers. These cookies store the information on

  * when and on what device a click on an advertisement occurred;
  * the advertiser’s affiliate program;
  * the publisher;
  * the specific time of the user’s action.

While tracking we may also collect information on the device that is used to perform a conversion such as its operating system and browser.

The purpose of this data processing is to track conversions (leads and sales such as installing an application or placing an order in an online shop) and to allocate them to proper publishers. It is necessary for the performance of a contract with third parties (our advertisers’ and publishers) that make use of our services, Art. 6 sec. 1 lit b) GDPR.

If you do not want Admitad to collect and store your data, click the button below to opt-out. Please note, that it may affect the functionality of the websites that Admitad works with, e.g. you may not get a reward for a purchase from a cashback website.

the opt-out widget is loading...

Our tracking cookies are listed below.

**Domain** | **Cookie name** | **Cookie lifetime** | **Cookie description and purpose**  
---|---|---|---  
.ad.admitad.com | clk_camp | 3 days | 

Set when showing banners of an Admitad tool called [Ad Server](https://help.admitad.com/en/topic/103-what-is-ad-server/). Stores the program ID of the banner in order to avoid showing banners of the same program twice.

_Example:_ 5a6c8893ac  
  
.ad.admitad.com | 10-symbol program ID | 1 year | 

Set when showing a banner. Stores encrypted information about the ad space, affiliate program, banner. The cookie is used to keep the statistics and to assign the reward to the proper publisher.

_Example:_ 5a6c8893ac  
  
.ad.admitad.com | defcampaign_* | 3 hours | 

Set when showing a banner. Stores the ID of an affiliate program. The cookie is used to identify the program of the banner by default.

_Example:_ d6526ecee5  
  
.ad.admitad.com | UID | 2 years | 

Stores encrypted values: version, [uid](https://help.admitad.com/en/glossary/72-admitad_uid-2/), the expiration time of the cookie.   
The cookie is set when a user follows an affiliate link and is used for targeting the users. It is also used for assigning actions and rewards to the proper publishers and keeping the statistics on actions.

_Example:_  
expr=1562739058|id=\xf7Z\x93\x8b\ xc1\x8f\xb08X\x945x||v=2  
  
.ad.admitad.com | UID2 | No expiration date | The purpose and the format of this cookie are the same as of UID.  
  
_Please note:_ although we choose our business partners and clients carefully, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of websites and mobile applications operated by such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of such websites and mobile applications you visit for more information on what kind of data they are processing with the help of our services and technologies and how they handle any data they collect from you as well as the legal base(s) for that processing.  

#### 2.3.2  Information on cookies and third-party cookies

As a publisher, you are to inform users of your website not only about your own, first-party cookies but also about third-party cookies, including those placed by Admitad: their names, purposes and how the user may prevent cookies being placed on his/her device. All information about Admitad tracking cookies is available here. A user must give his/her consent to the use of both first-party and third-party cookies on your website before a cookie is placed.  

#### 2.3.3 Behavioral targeting

Admitad does not conduct behavioral advertising and does not collect data for these purposes. However, our publishers may use cookies for purposes of behavioral advertising.

For this reason, we would like to draw your attention to the possibilities to object against the collection of data for purposes targeted advertising on the following websites <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> and <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/en/> (for the European area).

## 3\. Data protection and transmitting to third parties

Admitad takes all technical and organizational security measures required to protect your personal data from loss, unauthorized disclosure or other forms of misuse. Data is stored in a safe environment that is not open to public access. Your personal data may be encrypted before transmission in certain cases (e.g. processing your login data). This means that – support by your browser provided – communication between your device and our servers will include recognized encryption measures.  
Our staff has been trained in privacy matters and in dealing with data and information, which they gain access to in a responsible manner.  
Please be aware that should you contact us via email, confidentiality of information therein may not be ensured. Third persons may have access to the contents of emails.

Admitad may transmit your data to:

  * Service providers — to assist or facilitate in the services we provide to our clients, but only if we contractually assigned these to process data on our behalf and, both ourselves and the subcontracted service providers comply with all requirements of commissioned data processing regulations pursuant to the German law on data protection; data is stored within the European Union and the European Economic Area;  
  * Advertisers and publishers in our network — to provide our services;
  * Social media platforms and third-party providers whose cookies and other codes are embedded on our website;
  * Companies that we control and subsidiaries of such to fulfill our contractual obligations provided that these companies are subject to this Privacy Policy or privacy guidelines ensuring at least equal protection for your data;
  * State institutions on the basis of mandatory national legislation.

We do not transmit data to other third parties unless you have given your consent thereto.

In the event that Admitad is acquired by or merged with a third party, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information we have collected from you as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we may not be able to control how your information is treated, transferred, or used.

## 4\. User rights

You have the following rights concerning our processing of your personal data:

  * Right to access;
  * Right to rectification;
  * Right to erasure;
  * Right to the restriction of processing;
  * Right to data portability;
  * Right to object (on grounds relating your particular situation) in case of processing of your personal data based on our legitimate interest (e.g. direct marketing);  
  * Right to withdraw your consent at any time in case of any consent-based processing of your personal data without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before your withdrawal; and
  * Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

You may exercise your legal rights by contacting us via email to [data-support@admitad.com](mailto:data-support@admitad.com).  
In case you registered as a publisher or an advertiser on our website, you may access your account and correct or delete some of your data by yourself.  
While observing applicable privacy legislation we will erase your data without any action required by you, if retention of your data is no longer necessary for the purpose pursued or retention is no longer allowed for any legal reason. We may restrict processing instead of erasing your data where legally not allowed to erase (e.g. legal obligations to maintain your personal data).

## 5\. Amendments

We may modify this Privacy Policy and our data security provisions at any time, in particular, if new laws and regulations need to be adopted or we regard amendments reasonable.

## 6\. Questions / Contact

For all questions and requests related to the security of your information, please contact us and our privacy officers [data-support@admitad.com](mailto:data-support@admitad.com)

External Data Protection Officer  
ePrivacy GmbH  
represented by Prof. Dr. Christoph Bauer  
Große Bleichen 21, 20354 Hamburg
